What's the difference between a proposal and an idea.
提议和想法之间有什么区别。
Well they're not that different but an idea might be something you just kind of throw out there to solve
好吧，它们并没有那么不同，但一个想法可能是你扔出去解决的问题
a problem or for any other reason and a proposal is meant to be a little bit more serious and it's usually
一个问题或任何其他原因，一个提案意味着更严重一点，通常是
something that you would prepare for.
你会准备的东西。
So a proposal is more like or could be more like a presentation.
因此，提案更像或可能更像是演示文稿。
You might even prepare a PBT a PowerPoint presentation when you discuss a proposal for solving a particular
当您讨论解决特定问题的建议时，您甚至可以准备 PBT 和 PowerPoint 演示文稿
problem.
问题。
Now let's say the particular problem is that staff members or the whole staff they're just not getting
现在让我们说特定的问题是他们没有得到的工作人员或整个工作人员
along very well.
相处得很好。
Maybe there are some issues and disagreements and a lot of you could call it drama maybe coming up every
也许有一些问题和分歧，你们中的很多人可以称之为戏剧，也许每一次都会出现
day and maybe this is because they just don't know each other very well.
天，也许这是因为他们彼此不太了解。
They don't have a chance to socialize.
他们没有机会社交。
And so there's a bit of frustration among the staff.
因此，工作人员中有些沮丧。
Let's say this is the issue and one person is going to propose a solution to the problem.
假设这是问题所在，一个人将提出解决问题的方法。
OK.
好的。
And I'm going to just read out this proposal.
我将宣读这个提案。
I don't want to focus too much on the proposal because really it has the basics or the essentials of
我不想过多关注提案，因为它确实具有
giving a presentation.
发表演讲。
And we've talked about that before because you could stand up and you could make a little hook.
我们之前已经讨论过这个，因为你可以站起来，你可以做一个小勾手。
So you might say What do you think really is the core of this issue.
所以你可能会说你认为什么才是这个问题的核心。
It's pretty clear to me that the core of the issue is that the staff have no chance to socialize and
我很清楚问题的核心是员工没有机会社交和
form bonds with each other.
彼此形成纽带。
So we've maybe used a bit of a rhetorical question there.
所以我们可能在那里使用了一些反问。
Why do you think that we're not asking anybody to answer it right.
为什么你认为我们没有要求任何人回答正确。
They're just thinking about it.
他们只是在想。
So we're using a lot of the basics of the presentation that we learned in another lesson.
所以我们使用了很多我们在另一节课中学到的演示的基础知识。
So I don't want to focus too much on it but basically I just wanna make it clear that an idea is more
所以我不想过分关注它，但基本上我只是想明确一点，一个想法更重要
casual and a proposal is more formal and often something that you would prepare in advance.
随意，建议更正式，通常您会提前准备好。
OK.
好的。
So to the problem of issues with company culture bad morale company morale is low morale is the sort
所以对于企业文化问题的问题 士气低落 企业士气低落是那种
of energy level or level of happiness among the staff.
员工的能量水平或幸福水平。
I propose a big monthly dinner for the whole staff.
我提议为全体员工每月举行一次盛大的晚餐。
This will promote company culture and boost morale boost means to increase or to make it better.
这将促进公司文化和鼓舞士气的提振手段，以增加或使其变得更好。
Then I would probably go into more detail about why I think this is a good idea.
然后我可能会更详细地说明为什么我认为这是一个好主意。
Let's say we have a PowerPoint behind us based on the PowerPoint that we have.
假设我们有一个基于我们拥有的 PowerPoint 的 PowerPoint。
It could say for example.
例如可以说。
So this would be a good investment for us because right now if we have this issue with low morale having
所以这对我们来说是一笔不错的投资，因为现在如果我们遇到士气低落的问题
a big company dinner is something we only need to do maybe once a month that can allow the whole staff
大型公司晚宴是我们每月只需要做一次的事情，可以让全体员工
to get to know each other better.
更好地了解彼此。
Create new bonds in a relaxed setting.
在轻松的环境中建立新的纽带。
And when they can do that when they can have fun with each other then they're going to build trust.
当他们能够做到这一点时，当他们可以互相玩得开心时，他们就会建立信任。
And when they build trust those bonds are going to translate back into the workplace.
当他们建立信任时，这些纽带将转化为工作场所。
Then we could go on and we could go through our outline point A point B in Point C with examples.
然后我们可以继续，我们可以通过示例在点 C 中遍历我们的轮廓点 A 点 B。
I don't want to get into the whole thing but basically when you're giving a proposal follow the basic
我不想进入整个事情，但基本上当你提出建议时，请遵循基本的
structure of the outline that we learned in the other lesson.
我们在另一课中学到的大纲的结构。